♫ Brilliant sparkle, the color of jade
♫ Changing tears of sadness
♫ Into a smile of joy
Zunko Tohoku
Zundanon
♫ That's the mysterious power of zunda!
♫ (Wrap!)
♫ Wrap the world with our zunda
♫ (Let's wrap it!)
Kiritan Tohoku
♫ Let's wrap the world with our zunda
Itako Tohoku
♫ Zunda, Super Scrumptious Chance
♫ Super Scrumptious Chance, Zunda!
Usagi Chugoku
Sora Kyushu
Metan Shikoku
Why isn't it burning properly?
Can't you do something
with your power, Metan?
The power of darkness...
My power exists to defy a cursed fate.
You should use your advanced chemical knowledge to handle it!
Then, let's use the ultra-high-performance solar cells built into Mark 2 as the heat source!
No!!
Solar system...
Crash...and burn...
What was that?
Kiritan-sama!
We have to finish preparing the zunda before Zun-nee-sama comes back!
My, Kiri-chan, you're such a thoughtful little sister for Zun-chan, aren't you?
Well, in that regard, I won't lose to you!
Zunda.... daaaaa.
What's wrong, Usa-chan?
Zunda is a mysterious food.
It's made from beans, yet it's green.
No way, no way... Usa-chan, have you never eaten zunda mochi?
Yeah.
Mark 2 hasn't either.
We're planning to try it
for the first time today!
Huh? Two people trying zunda mochi? This is getting exciting!
Tako-nee-sama, that’s...
What's wrong, Kiri-chan?
Hmm?
It has a rough texture...
with grainy bits...
I followed the recipe, and yet...
Let's see...
It's not good!
It's awful!
Folic acid 26.3 ㎍, potassium 47.6...
What do we do? We made so much!
Destroy the evidence.
No way!
Zun-nee-sama will be sad, you know!
But it's too late to fix them!
And look at the state of the stove!
♫ That's the mysterious power of zunda!
Zunda Arrow!
♫ Change the world with our zunda
Change!
♫ Change the world with my zunda arrow
♫ Zunda - Super Scrumptious Chance
This arrow...!
♫ Super Scrumptious Chance...
♫ Zunda!
♫ Brilliant sparkle, the color of jade
♫ A mild and sweet flavour
♫ Zunda Arrow...
♫ changes everything into zunda...
♫ That's the...
♫ Exciting...
♫ ... power of zunda!
No food compares to zunda!
It's the yummiest in the world, right?
As expected of Zun-nee-sama!
If Zun-nee-sama unleashes the Zunda Arrow,
everything becomes delicious zunda mochi!
And if you eat zunda mochi,
your skin will be like Zun-chan's thighs,
all plump and squishy!
They're not plump and squishy.
They're chewy!
They're chewy, you know!
Zunda, huh?
I can't just ignore this!
Kansai Shinobi
♫ N...
♫ A...
♫ T...
♫ O!
♫N...
♫A...
♫T...
♫ O!
♫ It's name is...
♫ Natto!
♫ Whisk it!
♫ Smell it!
♫ Sticky strings!
♫ The invincible nattokinase!
♫ Improves blood flow
and makes flawless skin
♫ Boing! Boing!
Color...
Stickiness....
And the aroma—
Chanko's natto today is amazing!
Ooedo Chanko
It's always wonderful—everything
is orderly and clean.
Hokkaido Melon
Chuubu Tsurugi
Okinawa Awamo
Kana Robot
Perfect!
No need to praise me, Tsurugi. I know.
Huh? Where’s Shinobi?
Kansai Shinobi has returned!
Supreme Bean Commander, bad ne-
You fool!
This natto factory forbids any bacteria other than nattokinase! I told you not to contaminate it!
Nattokinase: an enzyme extracted from natto, a traditional Japanese food made from fermented soybeans.
S-S-S-S-S-Sorry!
So, what's the big trouble?
Well, actually... blah blah blah...
Blah blah blah?
What?!
Changing the world with
zunda mochi? How audacious!
Zunda is no threat to natto-
Soybeans and edamame are the same beans, just harvested at different times!
I can't stand them being
wasted on something like zunda!
All soybeans are destined
to become natto, you know!
Chuubu Tsurugi!
Yes!
Kansai Shinobi.
Hokkaido Melon!
Yes.
Okinawa Awamo!
Yes!
Crush the Zunda gang and scatter the nattokinase everywhere!
Never!
All for the sake of natto!
Terrible news! Edamame's price
has gone up ten times!
The drought killed the edamame!
At this rate, we won't be able to make zunda mochi anymore!
Our last edamame...
Our last...
...zunda!
No, no!
Always smile, or else the
precious zunda will turn salty!
Yes!
Who is it?
We're travelers, and we're starving!
Please spare us something to eat!
My! That sounds tough.
I know! Take this.
This is my last zunda... If I give it away, I...
But, I can't hog all the zunda...
That'd make me...
...unworthy of being called a zunda lover!
Please enjoy this—
Zunda mochi. The pride of Tohoku, and a world-class specialty!
Shekwasha!
What is this?!
It's as sweet as anko paste!
But it's also fresh!
I've never had anything like this!
I ground fresh edamame with sugar
and topped it on soft mochi!
Edamame...
Which means soybeans?
Natto!
What are you...!
Zunda? What’s that?
So lame!
Gross!
A green-colored food? Yuck!
Right?
That's not true!
Even zunda...
When it comes to beans, it's
gotta be red bean paste!
Yes, of course, red bean paste!
Natto!
Zunda is packed with
nutrients and so refreshing!
And besides-
Bzz, bzz!
Zunda mochi can't even be a main dish!
As a dessert, it's way too plain!
Plus, it's way too obscure.
Neither "zun" nor "da" has any coolness at all!
It's like, "no thanks!"
Compared to that, natto is...
Just so pure and simple!
I want to prove them wrong...
But...
What...
...is this brown stuff?
Th-This color...
It's the miso you put on Kiritanpo!
Kiritan!
and...
Itako-nee-sama!
Bleh, salty! You're the worst!
This is too much salt!
You can't appreciate miso's umami?
You're such a baby!
Such an unsophisticated palate...
We've heard enough from you!
Ta-da!
I'm...
Awamo Okinawa!
Ehe!
I'm Melon Hokkaido!
Sugar Water
Come on!
Mask Mode!
Melo-melo!
No!!!
Firearms? Not fair!
Hold it right there!
Yay, we got you!
Eat this!
Our righteous pop gun!
Kiritan! Itako-nee-sama!
- Zun-nee-sama!
- Zun-chan!
Huh?
Zun-nee-sama’s soft, squishy skin...
Her squishy skin is invincible!
Zundamon!
♫ That's the exciting power of zunda
Zunda...
Arrow!
Dohn’t gloph!
Next time, it's the end for zunda!
Hey! Wait!
Why...
How could zunda become
the cause of conflict...?
♫ Why, why?
♫ Did you disappear?
♫ Soybeans that mature fast
♫ Edamame
♫ Why did you disappear?
Master!
Where are you?!
♫ You withered before you bore fruit
♫ The meaty vegetables of the fields
turn into natto
♫ Stir it to your heart's content
then serve it on a bowl of rice
♫ Sprout and grow soybeans
♫ bear plenty of big beans
♫ Fulfill us (Fulfill me)
♫ with the power of soybeans
Oh! Aren't you Tohoku Zunko?
Huh?
Wait! Why do you hate zunda so much?
Hate? That word doesn't even come close!
It was the worst memory of my life!
I thought it was avocado dip!
But instead, the taste of zunda spread in my mouth!
Do you understand how I felt at that moment?
I'll never forget that disappointment and shock!
Huh? But, that...
I will never forgive zunda!
Never!
Sora-chan!
Run, Master!
Are you okay? ...Usa-chan?
Are you going to run?
We won't let you get away!
You're as tiny as a grain of natto!
Insolent! Stir them up!
Natto!
Huh? Awamo? Melon?
Zunda and natto...
What a foolish dispute.
For real! Compared to this red bean paste...
Their existence is small!
Don't say "small!"
Now, now, Ankoku General...
Why not show a "big" heart?
Don't call it big either!
How dare they fight over
something so small...
Note: "Ankoku" translates to "darkness" in Japanese, but it also cleverly incorporates 'anko,' which refers to red bean paste, tying into the bean theme.
Ankoku General
and call themselves "big beans"!
Someone like me, who bears the title of “general,” should not...
...have to acknowledge
soybeans as “big beans”!
Shame! Shame on them!
The master is even strict on herself!
She's not sweet on anyone.
Of course.
Unlike edamame, zunda, natto, and miso...
...those crafty soybeans who change depending on their use,
We azuki beans have always been devoted to red bean paste!
And yet, they dare call themselves “big beans,”
Big beans
while we are left to call ourselves “small beans”?!
Small beans
From now on, soybeans will be annihilated!
Azuki beans will become the supreme king of beans!
Red beans! Red beans!
Supreme Bean Commander!
You all...
You hoarded all the soybeans for yourselves!
Even if nattokinase forgives you,
Chanko will never forgive you!
We didn’t do anything like that!
Don’t play dumb! It's pointless!
But... we don't have that kind of money!
Huh? What did you say?!
Then, who did?!
I'll tell you!
The one who hoarded all the soybeans... was me!
The Ankoku General!
Ankoku General?
We bulk-bought all the soybeans
with the money we made with red beans!
No one can resist the sweetness of red bean paste!
Right?
You two... you betrayed us?!
That's outrageous.
I'd prefer you call it “switching sides,”
Little Bean Commander.
Didn't you two like natto?
Hmm, I'll eat it if it's there.
But I'm fine with or without it.
No way...
Hahaha! After all, soybeans...
...can't even compare to azuki beans!
Let's end this once and for all, little one!
Bring forth the Great Azuki Cannon!
Great Azuki Cannon
Chanko-chan!
Zu-nee-sama's boingy skin!
Her zunda power... disappeared...
Zun-nee-sama!
You! Why did you do that to Chanko?!
Because... we're all part of the soybean family.
Even azuki beans... too.
Kidney beans, chickpeas,
Peas, fava beans,
Peanuts...
We're all part of the same family!
♫ Beans... small and round...
♫ But... when you hold them,
♫ you feel strength welling up.
♫ Stay by my side forever
♫ I'll make sure I take good care of you
♫ I'll stay by your side forever and ever
♫ Give us plenty and plenty of...
♫ Harvest...
No!
Weren't azuki beans and
soybeans supposed to be rivals?!
Weren't they irreconcilable enemies?!
I... I...
Natto mochi... looks delicious...
And...
Zunda mochi and ankoro mochi...
I want to eat both together...
Zun-nee-sama!
Zu-chan...
Huh?
I'm...
Zunko!
All your tears have brought Zunko back to life!
Mochigami-sama
The Mochi God!
It's the Mochi God!
Tohoku Zunko, your feelings have reached me.
Yes!
- Oedo Chanko...
- Yes!
- Ankoku General...
- Y-Yes!
Both natto and anko are my precious daughters.
Now, celebrate! Before mochi, we are all family.
Yes!
♫ Mochi, mochi, mochi mochi!
♫ Anko and natto, zunda mochi
♫ Daikon, yakinori, cheese, and ketchup
♫ Daikon, yakinori, cheese, and ketchup!
♫ Anko and natto, zunda mochi!
Huh? We're out of zunda mochi!
♫ Mochi, mochi, mochi mochi!
I'm on it!
Zunda Arrow!
Huh? Everyone turned into zunda!
Hey! No fair!
Oh geez!
More anko! More anko!
Zun~oopsie!
The End